<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ML on XIAOYIJ</title><link>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/tags/ml/</link><description>Recent content in ML on XIAOYIJ</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Yi Chen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mrr1vfe.io/tags/ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>k-means in python</title><link>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/k-means/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/k-means/</guid><description>K-means There are two major steps in the K-means algorithm. The first one is to calculate the representatives (centroids) of a given partition. The second one is to find the partition based on the representatives.
Inputs Suppose we have a dataset looks like this:
1dataset = np.array([[5, 6], 2 [6, 5], 3 [0, 1], 4 [1, 0], 5 [3, 3]]) Each row in this dataset matrix is an observation and each column in this matrix represents a feature.</description></item><item><title>Understanding, Analysis, and Comparison of Convolutional Neural Network Architecture</title><link>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/ece532-final-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/ece532-final-project/</guid><description>Understanding, Analysis, and Comparison of Convolutional Neural Network Architecture A final project for ECE532
By: Yi Chen, Yuehan Qin, Jijie Zhang
Introduction [Yi Chen, Yuehan Qin]
Neural networks, which are widely applied in deep learning, are inspired by neuron connectivity patterns that are similar to animal cortex structure. A specialized neural network, convolutional neural network (CNN), takes the advantage of &amp;quot;convolution operation&amp;quot;. This operation, realized by a kernel or a filter, calculates the weighted sum of pixel information in a certain area defined by the size of the kernel.</description></item><item><title>Matrix Methods in Machine Learning</title><link>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/cs532/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/cs532/</guid><description>Unit 2 Linear Independence and Rank in Learning Linear independence A set of $M$ vectors $v_1, v_2, \cdots, v_m \in \mathbb{R}^N$ is linear independent if and only if \[\sum^M_{i=1} v_i\alpha_i = 0 \Leftrightarrow \alpha_i = 0, i = 1, 2, \cdots M.\] Otherwise, it&amp;#39;s called linearly dependent. A matrix multiplication of $Aw = d$ can be interpreted as the linear combination of the columns of $A$, where the weight for the $i^\text{th}$ column is the $i^\text{th}$ element of $w$.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Artifical Intelligence</title><link>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/cs540/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mrr1vfe.io/posts/cs540/</guid><description>Basic Python, comparing to Java 1 Why are we using python? It has a large amount of better machine learning libraries. Useful link Online Python compiler Key differences from Java Do not bother with a class unless you actually want to make an object. Functions do not need return types (or parameter types). Indentations matter, not {}; begin functions with : and end by unindenting.</description></item></channel></rss>